there is a subsection in the notes to
take a look at that and give yourself
setup in-class slash eleven
and pull down the uh... or about five
runs off the radar
but if you
copy this link
he will give you the whole link to the
or file
we're going to using the term or
whatever
so we've been working with the split
he met someone side and uh...
the terminals actually
the good idea
yet were evident terminal any max
together
and so i would
because when i recommend using a regular
terminal as opposed to term onsite he
max
but if you want to use our there it's
going
says he is the head and buddy
as little weird to kill a kiss
reinstalled thought he might have to be
disabled
uh... you can turn
are off
things so if tools click on add ons
into should be one of those icons is
like a
yet
uh... so extensions i think
yahoo looks like it's disappeared
it's possible the firefox update itself
and
acutely bag
no no
so on the virtual machine if you are the
usual research tools
that if you are logged into the research
tool servers
and anyway the point of c_n_n_ went
there
while we are
ballroom today
keep it
so make sure you get the uh... or fall
down
rights and offer it to log into the
aristide today for a class and i'll try
and do a better job of answering
questions inside the irish sea
i'm interning keep it open inside of you
max here
with the uh... p_r_c_ clients
which is an attack line for he max i'm
not very familiar with it
and today
last time we showed you the very
beginning said of looking at
i fight on and then use the plots today
we're going to start filling up
knowledgebase with python
in terms of simple detected we can use
without having to into know too much
it's got all kinds of nice functionality
for us
they're really help out and make it easy
to write programs
i'm hoping that
unlike bash which was kind of quirky in
every single way we ran into
i thought is designed to be very uniform
and some more
so that hopefully it looks the same as
you go through it
couple announcements
remember that homework three is due
today
i'll show you a little hints on homework
three for those of you are having
trouble
for today
there's a playlist on
you see a for the videos
and i've created
the growth of seven videos now
that runs in the range of fifty minutes
to you almost a half an hour video seven
covers a lot of material in class day
but not all of it
if you're having trouble with the bass
cell
parts one and two
go over
the basics and
a little bit different way than i do
anything here
so hopefully the slight variations will
help you figure out parts if there's any
trouble
if you're having trouble understanding v
section in the homework for homework
three recruit the file name
research tools video six batch party
variables will help you understand
variables
it's like specter
you guys are watching those and keeping
up with them
there for a long but hopefully will give
you the way down follow along
we won't go over
things like matlab and mathematica
too much if it on this class
but they're useful to know about and
very powerful
so next uh... monday
on the ten th at two p_m_ over in
kingsbury
there will be a presentation
going over some of the the stuff in
mathematica that's pretty cool
mathematica has a heavy focus on a
repeatable research so
you're basically building up a document
that is your
and your description and your plots and
so some of that
the stuff in repeatable research and
that sort of
area of interest
they developed a mathematica and people
are copying some of the functionality of
mathematica
advice for self
house or mention
that you age has and i_t_t_ newsletter
called signals
important announcements for the u_s_
community terms of computers
there's an article by our chief
information officer or c_i_o_
in the most recent one at some notes in
here about how i disagree with what she
said
i think a rat
and justice on changing passwords is a
little bit over exaggerated and i want
to remind you guys to focus on having a
different password for each account
and think about keep at saks to help you
there
watching us read out on your own
and let's talk quickly about
your
so you are having trouble coming up with
the file name and i gave you
something that looks like this
in a homework as to where to submit your
homework
so if i do
copy
paste that into here
what i gave you was actually a shell
script command that will actually
generates the name of your file
so i was expecting a type in the year
month day i was really asking you
to use a command in the shell
degenerates pyrmont they have right now
if you typed in two thousand eleven
al four
i knew what he did that before today
that you were sending from europe and
that's ok
the idea was that you can actually do
this by hand
or you can do it a shell script so
bc he replied
created following these eco test it out
in this account
this section here with the dollar sign
and black print see reference e
runs often runs the date command
suffragists grab that section
and paste it
echo
it's the equivalent of
just rang date by itself
and has the syntax where you can specify
which part of the day you'd like to see
says you're building up scripts in the
future think about
automating yours your process is so
if you do something every engineering
airport for the day when you're on the
ship
why don't you have the code actually
write out the file name with that did so
you don't have to remember
what's the date because you might be at
sea going across the dateline it can get
really confusing
you can actually create the commander
knows about time zones or you can ask
for
you can see
you cast for the uti cd
or third time zone
and so that way
we generate log files their always had
the same way
and you haven't i priority review
say by starting date myself i might say
two thousand
eleven
ten grow four
and happily go on
and if you noticed here
my ear is actually
quite a bit far in the future
if you add an extra zero in there
so every time you type stuff
your potential for
making a mistake
so use the computer to do things for you
so that you have more time to focus on
your science and spend less time
thinking about
what day of the week is it
so hopefully if you have it on the
homework yet and this gave you some
trouble this might
give you a better explanation of what's
going on
and you can see i try to on my
laptop
which is a mac and has a different
looking path and you'll see over on the
research tools one
which over here was
so it could knows how to deal with each
machine and i don't have to worry about
the changes between computers
okay here's a link to that
today's class video
so if it and before we begin a python
i'm appointed some resources but you
need to remember that there are two
major groups of python right now
the pipe on in the wild
you know subpoena
there's python three which is the new
fancy version of python
that's
dotson slightly different features and
syntax than the fact that we're using
raising typed onto
so if you start seeing dr addition of
python three new use it
it's close to what you want but there's
a few though things are going trip you
up
try to stick with python two
documentation while doing stuff with
this class
in fact some of the
to mature and two points to
the default is actually a python three
documentation need to be looking at the
python two point seven
that's good change in the next couple
years but we're not really sure when
and i've got in here for you
some links to the quick references uh...
link for our i've python quick reference
link to some books
the book that i think it's probably the
best for beginning if you want are
totally different way of thinking about
beginning python is driving a pipe on by
mark program
both free and for sale so if you are
supporting offer you can buy the book
but you don't have to do
and there's a wiki book where you can
actually change the book if you don't
like what's in there
think fight on is the computer science
way to think about right on
and that's not what in the trend in this
class i think by phone
is what a computer scientist with think
about
and try to do approach by tommorow avoid
that
fighter pilot on is
one were actually going to straight at
fight on three t and watch out for that
and data structures not rhythms is
another one that's very computer science
e
if that's helpful to you prefer to go
for those
now the last one
is that we are going
it's the programming historian
so these are two
professors to do
history research
and so their point of view is from
historian and not a cure scientist is
very much like this course in that
they're focused on
computing for history
and i have no idea with us really liked
but they use things like that era for
demographic references
she'll find out
another completely different view
fight on
that might be helpful if you're not
understanding what's going on this class
i meant to give you some links to books
in safari and i am amounts of it'll fix
america
in here for afterwards
bear some really fancy stuff you can do
when you're inside of my python where
you can ask it to edit files for you
animal then pop open
email acts
i'm natalie that for you guys to work on
and will get wilt
get back into that will definitely use
it on thursday
went through here just set it up front
and you guys can see it
it's very very he need to be able to be
an ipod phone just after erika please
open at this file
and then you can tell from the max
doctype right on that you're done
editing
so that's that's really nice the one
thing you have to watch out for the
default mode
drops you into a program called the i
if you ever c_d_i_
which is i i see a budget
twenty percent
there's one b i command to know
catsup colin
akeel explosion point
they were not that that's right you know
about it wonderful now
this is the command too quick out of the
i without stating whatever filing or
anything
that barry if he can and i remember from
the eye
and above all others
adapted but that's the one that i want
everybody to know
if you get stuck in the eye
it's really hard to put out of it
he doesn't like control senior controls
the yield the jewels
colin q
that gets out of you guys
sort of you'll may hit that today past
may not realize it until
i'll point you thapar whiteboard
so they surely imax worried or not
it's the fun part of python
but overall
and start by pune
in that directory
had one i think on
then only i would've said make sure you
add the dash dash by lab
or not they do it by today so i can make
that out
and make sure if you are print working
directory p debbie dvd-ram
class eleven if you're not there you can
see teaching a class eleven if you're in
your home directory
so everyday type i thought it and it
appeared to be a make sure that you're
sitting in
class eleven
once you open up your ipod fun terminal
control you to clear loin
tell us
you cv in the wrong place sita cv
into class
the cd
c l_ a_ s_ s_
they are doing a lot
anything you in and katie i_r_a_
for make directory
space eleven
presenter
cd into their
space eleven
now you can do a and b_ loss if this
works and the space
and then tell the swatch
tilburg slash
amanda eleven
pressed count
space
and then period
now mister kerkorian
now doing dallas
so if you have failed to do or
org wrote files to the home directory
you could do a and b_ phyllis lives
eleven that
which and then i will press to tab ki to
complete so i don't have it there
but it would be i think the on
dot org
and put a period for the current working
record that were moving into your
current directory i'm not gonna run that
because i saved the file into my
current rectory
so if i do in our special you'll see
that i have
eleven dash i_ python dot org
serbian-run this study get commands
and i i i thought
if you're in a tight on you can you add
exclamation point
visit and i think the feature
uh... by python as you can run any back
shelf
whiny wind here
survive paste
that they be get command
right there and press enter
it's going to go off and get that file
and what did you get if you keep doing
it more pple times you'll end up with
uh... dot one q ten twenty
seating for a period after your room
to move to the destination so that the
other way
space
and then period
pleasant when you get the aha moment
open estimation point before that if you
get
if he started and i i don't
if you put it
and isolation point
and then the commands
in here you'll be running bash
so you were any dash commend you on
after that
available from the regular shell you can
get through by the spring escalation
point for the front
there's a couple weighs in
i fight on
to get help
the first one is you can go to
and if i click on that docs like you can
go to the fight on documentation and you
can read all about it
that there's a lot there free to get
lost
inside of my partner and we can get help
on anything that we run into you
so it's trying
so then that's helped and then open
i fight on sky nice for you it lets you
be lazy feels immediately see here
and i left out the parentheses on open
every wrote my command with parentheses
for me and said i'm gonna go run this
instead
so you'll see that you got a lot in
class
we could also say open and a question
mark
teja i don't know what this is
press enter
and you get lots more
i think to question marks
betrayed me more help
but looks the same
now this is kind of tough
you'll see a lot of stuff in here that
you don't necessarily understand
by the end of semester overstep becomes
familiar
it we can use the question mark and help
to get help on various things as we go
and we can also say
there's a question last time about exit
versus capitalize it
so if we do u anything with a question
on the other side you can say exit
as this one
exit out of python
it right see you in a statement or were
asking yes or no
if we ask about
capital exit
exit without confirmation so that means
if you type
exit two princes
it says i don't know what that is
exit yes
you are in the armoured
so use you
so you're in a
if you next yr bank here in nyc ls mode
it's a related to the uh...
uh...
view of a dell
at that time
exit exit quickly with a capital e
exhibit lower case keeps their
if you do help
and open here in this mode
this very similar thank you also works
without the collins execute
food
it's whichever side you're feeling like
so either side
you will do
i mean do you shift in time
amex collapse everything so i can get
myself sorted out
press tab in here
listed getting help
when you see some examples you guys have
been
very enthusiastic about the control c
control scenes
which i think is great
we didn't even when i didn't expect you
to
if you do you think this control c
control c evaluate on this section
i type yes
when i say prints one if we did ah...
one over here
it prints one looks great
were in have a little bit troubled doing
that so
don't expect this to work
frenzied media print whatever turns non
she's not really what you wanted
people away during this inside of here
is returned one you're gonna get results
he didn't expect and you'll get more
comfortable with this as we write
functions and understand
what a strategy for us so basically if
you do control c control c today when i
didn't ask you to
don't expect to see any results that
they actually meeting
there might be a whole lot of color the
looks like it should be doing stuff
anxious can ignore you
so we start our pipeline
collapse the section
so let's go ahead and start playing with
fight on inside of a ripe right on shall
before we do anything fancy
let's just start off by creating a
string
this is any saying
now python has
freeways to the strengths
seal see them all
you can do
a single quote
my string
you can do it double quote
and some tax
and then you can do
three
single quotes
so those are three different things in
there
and three single quotes
and syntax
if you see those any of the notes
we're just going to use the top one px
this guy right here
so that single quote around our
strengths
unfortunately this is one of pleasant
work and you can do a lots of ways and
with this confuse you
for starters so it's going to single
quotes for strings
for the press center
you get this is a strength
we can do things with strings we can say
this is a string dot
capitalize
weak acid to capitalize a string
we can ask it to you
uppercase that string so it's really up
with shouting at us
and we could do a lower if we wanted
we can also ask you to make it like a
title
where capitalizes the beginning of
each word in there
so there's lots of functionality with
each of these objects
we can even add strings together
it might sound a little weird to be
adding strings
they're not really numbers
and so in python sometimes
things like the plots
try to give you a meeting that makes
more sense for object so we can say
this is
group lawson between each one
stirring
what does it do them all together
except for it doesn't have the concept
of a space between those you actually
have to admit faces you won't have a few
wanted to actually be flexible
so you can start building up things if
you're going up a consensus and
something rebuilding a report
you could
put in the number in between eight that
you want to have
and it was then circling your report
now python has a nice feature that you
can ask it
what the type of something else
this is a strength
ever turns back it's a nasty are which
is short for string impact on
we could also ask
the number one that is not now
will pick a different amber about thirty
three
as in say that's an interval integer
so let's take a look
at the data types in python this is what
we're gonna builds
the class of are these little components
as you go along you're going to using
these
to keep your date around in various
forms and work with
as your build your programs
so let me just walk through these
and give you a sense of 'em up on the
white ford so we've got something to
hang on to you
we've gone strings and that's
referred to you by s t r
we've got numbers
and if you're a scientist this where
life gets exciting right you can
actually have numbers of things and
could stuff
we have a couple different types we
haven't integers
and that's like
the number one
or to you
or negative five
etcetera
we have floats
cozier real numbers so one point
team to reinforce five
minus six point one
zero
period
if you want zero to be a floating point
number you have to have appearing in
there
or you could say how about
one point two ye
twenty points
so that something to the power of twenty
one
so that's a pretty big number
hopefully should take it the strike real
quick
sold one point to use the twenty-one
that's a pretty big number
we also have what are called
pools or boolean
and i might be a little surprising of
needs that were never capillary
but once you see what boolean czar
in terms of apostles eyes you probably
get pretty quick that's
one possible is true
and everyone is false
this is the yes no true false world
with referred us boolean or
invite on its for
for mike that's you'll see that a lot
and if you do not connect asked
then they tell us whether to boolean
or the true value
is true or false
we also have
lists for sequences
and these artists a series of stuff
some of them are or some of them or not
the most commonly used
is our list
and this is britain with square brackets
and inside can be a number of things
they have like minus two
one point nine
the word
so you can put anything in there
they don't have to be the same type you
can start putting things together
we have something called to polls
to pose a risk their lives that are less
powerful so form i can talk too much
about those areas the sometimes print
the seas
sets sets are fine
as you go through data so you're reading
a list of ship names and there's lots of
duplicates
if you go into a set and you keep adding
ship names
you have the same name my ten different
times it's only a keep wanted of that
so it's a set contains
only up to one so here analysts we could
have
the number one following along for black
three followed by one
that's okay
intercepts
if we send sat down
one one
we're gonna get back
and three
so if you're trying to find unique set
of things
that's a nice way to do it so featuring
three day that's often
serena set of u_s_ strings these uh...
'cause we saw from our g_p_s_ upstairs
you could pull those out of each
sentence throw them into a second
accurate early because he which
which nina sentences that i have
one that's actually really handy that
you probably in if using a lot is called
the dictionary
and what this has
is it's going to be a set where you have
a key
and a value
if you have a key you can ask the
dictionary
do you know about that so
are key could be
geology
and then to go with it could be any
value
and they said that if you look up table
where if you want to store values for
something
you could have the speed he can be a
name and number
a number of different things
and then you have a value go with it so
it's a
matching preparing at things
and we'll go through examples of each of
these
and see them
there's also to other ones that are
pretty important
on the other one is
so we can have files that we can open
be able to meant the keeping there is
really use the word open
especially one called non
and will see that a few times
none represents nothing
it's no i didn't have anything to give
you some of you know on
or you don't have a value for you
so not as have a special case will keep
running into and hope we'll get a feel
for it down the road
so those of the basic types of things
were used to build up programs
and there are more acts and control
logic for it
so let's do
a little bit of i've typed on before we
dig into these days has it's going to
help us
figure things out
there's chicken and say what you guys to
know crew and
whose
so the type who
there's nothing in our space this is
our commander people often use 'em out
very similar events
the tells you all the variables that are
in your working space if you do shoes
through the same thing there's nothing
so let's just say
ship name
equals
harvey
cogeco
so you might know much at
and now for a typo
itil says a ship name
if i can spell ship right
kitten
who
now is to love them
i can do it deleted of a variable
minus filled ship name
appetite to attend you can see that it's
gone
if a type of shoes you got to see the
values that go with a particular
variable
so if you're working with tested a
second i python near trying to figure
out how to do something
this is a great way to look into your
workspace and see whether overloaded if
you're doing a pretty big problem or a
few hours you might forget what
variables you have loaded up into the
system
who and who's our great tools to go look
at what's in there
can change the type of variable
yep and we'll talk about that some
aerials can we change in other types of
variables and will show some examples of
that
with such a with numbers will be had a
convert numbers to and from strings
there's also
a command that you may want to have
finance called log start
sify do an ls dash l first
there's nothing up my sleeve
miss a log starts
and what this does is gonna record your
session to a file
so if you wanna go in later on and find
that you could type history
and copy paste that into a max
and deal with it that way
but with
log start you know i writing a file
and their status file called pipe length
on blog
pot and you can actually
talented
pick a different name
but this way you're recording your
session
and so if you're really working for a
problem you don't want to worry about me
taking notes for a while you really need
to think about it
a lot of a great way to see what's going
on and then come back and pick out the
piece is a good one
and then you can say log
and it's done
noticed there's a special magic commands
feel sometimes see it with a percent
you can leave those often it will cast
those
there were too much about these funny
magic commands but if you see the
percent
a special i fight on only tool
so now you've got a lot of well if you
want it
and i will say
start myself
make sure it's
profound therein noticed that is
actually going to keep
other stuff around and to some backups
its kind nice
and let's try it out someday types
so i think it's best just to see these
things in action
and get a feel for what they can do you
so it's open up the strings one
instrument i check name equals
coastal
surveyor
and we'll see what we can deal with this
ship name variable
we cast the length of it
america was pressed tab your part way
through so ship
i'm in town
so we have sixteen characters
we can ask for a particular character
v square brackets after variable
is for about lookup into this list of
things
so zero will be our first
in python
organized think by computer scientist
semister accounting firm zero
so if you ask for one it's not the first
letter it's the second letter
we can ask for arranger of things so
let's get the fifth thirty eight
characters and their
and it's going to give you was that
position
five
six
and seven
we can find a letter so let's go back
here
if you have a very bold amy put it dot
and then something after it
that's something that comes with dot
object
so it's got
a bunch of things that knows how to do
simply type find
animal picked the letter s
hopeless off on the letter at somewhere
in there
and water s is that position aids
now what we can also do is now if you
know where it is
you can say give me think everything
from position eight on
by leaving out
this part
eileen leblanc in there you go to the
end
if we just want the second word from the
newest urban ask you can get
we could also come from the back
so minus one is the last character
stuff are
if we do minus four
that's the heat
and again if you do a colin
and go to the end
cesium sliced apart as string
get different bits of it
if we ah...
keep going here
think that's the same text repeated
summer exciting
and spit out and try some numbers
we can do the number one and that's a
number of students a type one at singer
we can do one point one
you get back one point one
and you can say tight of that
and that's a floating point number
so that will be again this
range of things in there
if you've done that well before you
should be bored by now
but we can say
three point one four one five
this is how it changes string into a
number
and so that converted to a number so we
can and say what is the type of what we
got back and actually converted that
string and single quotes into a number
now what if we didn't something kinda
crazy here
and that's going to work
probly not i don't know the number would
be for that
as they tell you there's a value error
could not convert string
to flow
few gonna start seeing some of their
messages will start small
and you'll actually get
comfortable with them
they can be a little overwhelming
sometimes in big programs to get what's
called the traceback
and and might tell you a lot
what more then you're ready four
so hopefully this will get you uh... a
slow start that
let's do something
kinda funny what word
decent called
import mass
import goes off and brings in some extra
functionality we might want
so important math
it's a map up high
suddenly we don't have to remember the
number for pi it's given to us
we can do math dot sign
now thought
hi divided by two
and will get back
ensuing radians here for us
with golf it's a malfunction zone there
picking things like convert from radians
degree three iseries agrees to hear that
nafta radians
one eighty
so if i remember right that should be
height
to get that politics
and if we did
tends to you
dreams as to buy it
we can also do you math dot degrees
tee times math
dot klein
guessing that's all the way around the
circle so if i remember right they
should be three sixty
so there's degrees
we don't really know what's in there
you've got this march along we haven't
looked inside so we can take math period
and tab
and it will list off all the things that
are inside of their continues
and for now
if you see underscores
please don't worry about them just
ignore them pretend they don't exist
anything with underscore etc
will be something fancy room i look at
later on but for now just look at things
like
laptop by
this is power
and so we can save
math dot power question mark
and if you go ask you what his power to
you
and here
he returns acts to the power of wine
now if you start doing things like
acoustics you might need a different
kind of math
you might need complex numbers we've got
those
for jane
there's a complex number
complex so it doesn't actually come as a
part of the math tools
so complex itself right into the paper
itself
the mac module was kind of like
parents tab which by sea
and uh... seventies were mathis
facts on the function sign function
trades and whatnot are not a part of the
normal system
we can also do complex math
so for j
for us
ora klein's take your favorite operator
q plus nine j
and we get back that
complex number
and if you do complex map you'll get
very familiar with this and you can use
it in
so's your basic numbers and strengths
let's go look at one of those containers
that we have here the sequence items
list and if you're the c_e_o_ use all
the time
school starts with a list
and maybe we want to create a list
as a sequence of numbers and i know
it was definitely have some of the
classes
for the our part how to make a range of
numbers because it really sucks type
our zero through
twenty three and i forgot zero in class
there's a command called range
if you take that this is where is very
clear that pipeline is coming from zero
it's going to give us five numbers
but since our from zero
so we'll see
zero one two three four but not five
you can also tell where to start
so we can start from two and so it's
going to give us
two three four but not five
with ranged we can also say
how often to jump
for how much jump
so still range three
so much twenty-eight
it's gonna jump by five spelling up and
still
but not including the highest number of
twenty eight so soon started three
jumped by fives
up to
twenty seven
bdsm but not put twenty
we can make our homeless which is
probably more interesting most of the
time
so let's say
uh... take a much simpler example ended
before
we have a tug
if the robo
and we have and
r_v_ for research vessel
separate used the wrong brackets
use the square brackets not the round
ones
this etype
we had a list
sovereign creo est
we can also up and to ship
we could certainly make it could
fathers
its happy to do it from his a type time
for temporary
at the table
vicious we can't now change that one
such a force fixed
into memory you can overwrite
i'm totally new to pull but you can't
change it so it's not very fun to work
with
triples you'll see them and people often
start learning to both but they're
really boring
like you can't add onto a simple
you can make a new two hole but you
can't change it
and i think it's really nice to just
mentally people change which are working
with
exist for speed
it's a great question
so if you have a triple
it uses much less memory it's a much
more
fast others to walk across the terms of
the system so if you have a lot of these
and say you have a chameleon
uh... lists of things
if you make them all less it's gonna use
more memory
and said take longer walk across them
you've got
you can always say
list
and will return back a list
we can also say
pupil
and ship
and get back triple from a list
it's easy to switch back and forth
and it doesn't matter too much and so
you get to really get a sense that you
really want to be easy to fool so for
beginning
just think about less and
when someone says to pull say i think
you mean less than a minute
that stephenson advanced stuff
so let's go back to our ship west
and in here if we can ask the length of
that swath of shift that three of them
but what if we forgot one
chip dot append
will say
passenger
and now for a look at shifts it's got
one more on the end
so we can then add to this
sky nice week a m
sort this list
noses won the trips people up including
myself pretty often
sort doesn't return anything
it sorts the worst in the actual list so
you can't than sort something in
assigned to another variable
you have to sort it and then later on
the side if you want to have a sort of
list separate
if i press enter it looks like nothing
happened
so swords kind of weird like that
if we tied
ship again now
notice that
here's the before
so shut off a tug
and here's the after or starts off a
passenger and time is now at the end so
it sort of them alphabetically
we can say ship
dot this sorts and we can ask it
you can
discourage ear which you're probably not
comfortable with yet
the c_m_v_ as you can pass it some
function and that does a comparison
anyway that you want
and that's a little more advanced deep
things like that but you can create a
function that sorts it and you can
define however it is that you want is
for good
america's youth home worked for fun
knows that for a while
this is where it takes a little while to
get used to reading the documentation
but they're compare right now
is a simple one this just alphabetical
and you have to write some function ever
turns negative ones here or one whether
or not mobsters last band peoples who
were great event
so it's really powerful
but it's going to get confusing pretty
quickly beginning
so we're not gonna worry too much about
this work and i forget that
we can't just like the string we can say
ships zero hitter first ship
we get the last year
with a minus one
and
we can also ask you what is ship so how
do themselves
uh... than sinker run aground ur
sewing here
we have always underscore methods you're
gonna totally ignore
and you know what just over here
at the app and counts index insert pop
on the roof
so they've got some things they can do
we can try some of those
and we can also try removed so ship dot
remove
and
within the safe talented
and now if we take a look at our ship
we no longer have
that tug on the air
we can also say
there's one called
pop which is takes one-off the end
wave your hands around or are not to
have any idea that you're having
troubles
so you could share ship carrying press
center
that's gonna give you an error because
you haven't told her what to do you
so you can do ship period press tab
and now you getting a list of functions
and then you talk to you type more stuff
after that
so it's a good one if you guys don't
leave your hands you're going to be
missing out on stuff that i assume
is obviously is not
so if you have all set of things
even pop one off the top
and
throwed out its uh... off the end off
the boat
writing inside
when she type ship dot t_ o_ p_ and
question mark and press enter and see if
it tells you
so hopefully it will tell us
so the falls as last yes
so ship period and now
the full stop
that time
and now you get a list
in the notes i call that ships within us
in class i just it shipped without an
ass
for the confusion there
that's a good misheard so ship question
mark
that soviet celeste if you say ships
question mark
object not found
i don't have a ship's remember the lou
there my variables or
whose
will show you the different there was
you've got and what's in them
now like for example if you look at this
map one
don't worry about too much ill start to
understand that down the road
that some guatemala joyous
for now i'll just use them without
worrying too much
so let's try something else here stuffed
with strings
new hunter restoring into a list of
breaking into pieces
will do
numbers
one-two-three-four
ninety-nine
so it's going great that numbers
variable
and what if we want a list of each of
those in a separate
i says make it more interesting
there's blistering since we did say
numbers
so remember that number is is not
an actual number
weekend
kicker numbers
toughing it out there's lots of
different functions but one of them is
right here is split
mccabe's split what is it to you
and what it does is it will break this
into
various chunks
on some for a separate that we want to
ask it so we can say numbers split
the defaults is a space
white-space
and so now
we have
our numbers per pinup into a list
where used please take numbers to greasy
agreeable
it's going to break it up on white-space
so it's nice to be a little break things
apart if we have
for example if we go
ship name
equals
challenger com ar harvey
maybe somebody likes to write
the type of a ship afterwards for the
comma
so they say that very boldly say shit
name
dot spoil it
it's not that he was what we want to
take a break in the gulf challenger
atacama will be inside of here cigs hard
to read
and then
r_v_ on the right
we want to split on that karma
so say i think you're dealing with
comma-separated value data
you can split on anything you want to
hear compressed return
as good a split on that comic character
and give this golf challenge ur
as the first thing
in our view is the second
so now we can say
here's the first one
and we just kicked off challenger
so still a bit more clearly will sing
fields
equals ship name
dot splits
and will split on the common
scenario this terrible caulfield
switches
should be a list
to the list
we can save name
equals
field sub-zero
what if it's gonna be a name
you only have a guess
co-founder axle yes sofa tightening
we get back culturalcare
no she also did some funny things we can
say name times four
leaders think
most petition with the string is going
to be kept
you typed as yell on
without the team
so its political neophyte parentheses
referencing
that's right fields and press enter
type who c have ships foro
seemed to do this
for using shipping
so tight
fields equals
ship name
and then do the split
sochet named dot split
so if you see a number ninety three
you see me partially going through
things so every time
i pressed tab
so i typed
i pressed how break here
if that your options are shipping ship
name
source tele ninety three i have
impressed answer yet
field equals ship name so i think we've
got to their pressed
that period or full stop
type exp l body
and i asked to finish for me
pressed count
and a selective use plates
or split lines
which we don't know about
and so here
i said i just want split
fischer in a way here i press enter so i
never pressed enter appear for either of
those plans
the only ones i have a full
commemorating
i pressed answer
that i've been
you see here
visit command
workplan at use it was a great question
and so when you see a jump from ninety
three ninety four
actually press enter
and ran the command
sitting when i want to hazard a guess
as to what made you find for
have a strange thing most
position too
uniformly correct
and what just happened here
that was lovely and so that was the
secret answer you couldn't see
cut their heads
looks like uh...
the enter key got stuck
filter yes you can do somewhere
functions like that
it might not matter much for you right
now but say you want to do something
like a big dashed line in your output
newark eighty characters of dashes
across the screen
it's helpful it's just not always
obvious why you might want to learn
about these things until you run into a
case where you're like awake
i can multiply that string times eighty
and i've got a big long lines
takut
i'm gonna go ahead and show
what i've done here so hopefully that
history won't look too terrible with the
uh...
million blank lines so history
over the uk
real data has real problems right
uh...
of the scrolling back here
so in here
command ninety-six is where iron maiden
name
so i grabbed the first one of the
entries in the fields in-store baton
verbal main
and then
in ninety seven i was just printing it
out by typing in his enter
animal qualified for
where does it take the string picks for
the man who's them together
they can't wonder
so if you want to joining together with
a particular character
and it's very it's a hard to read color
in the out but i need to get smarter act
my cascading style sheets which i don't
really know
let's say who
who's in suva dot here for a very both
let's take our attempt
skimpy variable
and i want to join it
with uh... space two dash is in the
space
this actually has something called
drawing
it doesn't always know for you to help
proportionally
but joining
t_n_t_
and what this does if you have a string
and you want to use it to join things
together
you called joint deposit a list of items
and it's gonna put this string in
between each of those items
so if i want to make at csd evidence
i cared if replace this with a comment
take all your fields
join in with a comma
and you now have a c_f_c_s had to try to
write yourself a csd file to go alone
into something like excel
numbers or openoffice early bird office
isn't how you might do it
uh...
uh... king
this is just out for any of the service
to the algeria's just reading it nowhere
so if you want to save it
who want to say
csd
now you have
i'm still getting snow some cores
arrived by parliament refugee stuff off
and i only just figure it out
i've had done it like a crusty bad way
that i didn't like
and so when i try and show you guys
i try to remove all of the stuff that i
learned it was bad and remove my bad
habits and only teach you to have it
i don't always succeed
but right
let's go ahead and create a file
summer learn how to write a file from
memory to read back in
you can just do a control c control
scenes like this block
but i recommend skipping that because
it's not as much fun
unfair how you define fun
and where to go ahead
and copy this
which is also met a w
went up a stunning
and what this is doing the open command
opens a file
flows water here open will open a file
here to give it a file name
so data dot csd
and this park here
the in quotes w says we want to open it
for breaks who want to be able to put
data into that file
it's important to know that
if you had some very important in that
file
the minute we run this command
you can wave goodbye to united as it
disappears
the w will stop on
or kill anything that there with that
name
presenter
and you know have
this new variable called final will say
tight
called out
which is of type file
and we can now say out dot right
so now we can write our data
one comment to you
slash and is a strange strengthened
diffusers
this watch that leans to the left
which is the one that's above your
return key
and then a character those have special
meaning
and if we'd want to put
a swatch in there
an actual sliced character we have to
duties flashes and that would turn into
a squash in the output
but slash and is a new line
if we didn't do this
you would have
all of your numbers on the same line in
trenton a big massive slash and put the
new line into
that string which then goes out to the
following right
school go ahead
press printer
and let's do this
two more times
different data
or come off on it
unions
nine com ar
minus one
that was needed profound is the comments
and then i was sort of showing you that
few slashes turn into a slash
a morning better to put a pound in there
to make sure that
when people just had to endure without
realizing that they haven't done
something completely crazy
it's not always obvious white
if i'm gonna write a note fucking look
what i'm doing it's confusing
closer per file and hopefully it works
there's one thing to remember about this
is that
think we're in the data
but i bet you um...
if we do an ls dash all look at our data
file
who can see the size of our dated ucsd
how big is that file
zero bytes
that's a little scary
when you write stuff itself was called
by offering
and doesn't put up the desk and tell you
say
i need to force the service can getting
out there
and one of the easy way do that is to
close the file the writing what's his
clothes it's going to finish writing up
whatever's left over to write
so we can say alex dot close
an alpha q alistair cell data dot c_
s_p_
i'm hoping
that we have
thirteen
let's go ahead and open that file
sophie you can chillax control f
i did a control extremists but first
soviet thirteen bites very small file
but it's a good start
there's data we can do with do stuff
with
there's lots of ways to create this in
the passages benedetti de tara curl to
go grab it
now churn i thought no
it's more fun to be created on your own
these type in the path to learning
something class eleven uh...
mindcrest haven't
and time again
the nation's ciated did not see if the
athens tech india tab
so it's in class all of them
so
till the slash c l_
press tab
first time again
they see that there's an eleven to
twelve eleven
steve open the directory uh... press
g_e_ in there
but just the letter g_ if you're
interested in the world
showing the terminal we rewrote the
final
couldn't bring a friend do api dvd
print working directory
see how you were in your home directory
so you didn't put it in class slash
eleven
so you have to go back to email x
is ok support for the country
and you can't relax control f
to until it's just tell the swatch
now press time
press d_n_a_ and tab
singer evidence yes he said in an area
that happen
thursday
events happen
into day also
going a terminal real quick
anti-peace lvgi in there
your thing is
the out dot close without the
parentheses
at the affair too that uh... you see the
same line again
and put left pretty right pretty
so it burns that uh... though function
citicorp up on the screen
at the end yet
so by putting a plant the seeds means
program that's
disclosing that that files have
and i'm going to completely avoid
a discussion of object oriented
programming if you hear that you can
close your ears
ang norick
you'll be doing object or a programming
but we don't care that we're doing that
doesn't mean that it's a lot of
vocabulary
that you'll hear a little bit
and we could spend six months talking
about it and i'd be really really boring
the fun
so we're gonna do
object type stuff and that's what this
is the little thought
and then some clothes and practices
we're running some functions attached to
some data
or file or something
sitting on a special
and do you have it the uh...
sixty yet there is apparently
so ceiling at front there didn't lions
did not see if you don't want and a
campaigns boldly risking their own
precedent
it just had a
i'm sorry you had to be that was good
till two slash
d_n_a_
and everything
they go now press enter
cheat on this pack type yes so if you
see a changed on disk that means that
something else has changed that file
and already knew about that
seed managed to open up your data cscs
and hope for that realizing it
that datafile got changed and then you
reloaded
kal let's go see if we can read this
data really quick in the last two
minutes we have here
you can't it's not
you might get ripped up on a couple of
things
such are you a void those little
pickups today if we could
so let's go ahead and do a quick example
of reading it
so to see that
commander book called datafile equals
open
and before break here ad
comma and then a single quote w saying
rights
the default is read which is a lot safer
than writing because you can step on the
data
depress enter here
and say type
datafile
it's a file that's great
if we
say datafile
read lines
this is uh...
read everything all at once before then
just to enter
we've now pulled in a whole bunch of
data
kinda went nowhere
reinstated so we can re-open the file
some escrow backup to my open command
if i run this again it's going to reopen
the file instrument back at the
beginning of the file
and we can say
deduct file dot
wine
and noticed that before we have three
lines quarrel witchcraft all of them
here we're gonna read one minute time
there's no ass in there
so just hit reply in
and you get back that first line of your
file
never do it again
the second line
the third line
and wait what
read lines perot
fifth
so datafile
read blindness
an imprint
that's just a
without the parentheses it's not gonna
actually run
so princy referencing you're gonna call
that
and even our approval filed yet
so the plane was read lines
so apparel
ted tab
okay so
he has not said
datafile modify instead decided
i think you're a few even
back before that
jeezy
d_c_ line two oh one up there on the
screen
so you need to do with what i have is
going to one on the screen today to file
equals open
data
csd
datafile equals
easy-going to a lot of them
if you don't open the file gets her with
that
single quote
deduct csd
quote
press enter
now you can do datafile thought
freed lines
so we are out of time for today
david lee seen some of the basics out
their holes
and green lines and files
please do watch the python video one
because you're very similar stuff
are also slightly differently
and the peso at your own pace because
you can hit pause reading here it's
kinda hard to make me pause
see how that goes i'm not going to do a
homer till next time and we'll keep
pretty simple
this is the basics of programming inward
we're doing what
in a typical computer science class in
with c programming
reading a file comes that condo a month
or two into doing see in here
you've been doing python for an hour and
forty minutes
so you're doing what i think your
scientist would do after two months of
study
in an hour and a half
don't feel it's going overhead
you're going really fast compared to
traditional ways heaps of stuff
but i'm hoping by
in the end of next week that you guys
will be able to regain
text-based data pretty comfortably